Privacy Policy
==============

Gofile is designed with privacy at its core. This policy explains what personal data we collect, why we collect it, how we use it, and the rights you have regarding your information.

Introduction & Scope
--------------------

Gofile is an online cloud storage and file sharing platform operated by WOJTEK SAS, a company registered in France. We are committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals who use our Service, and we have designed our platform to collect as little personal data as possible.

This Privacy Policy applies to all Users of the Gofile platform, whether accessing the Service as a guest, a registered free user, or a Premium subscriber. It describes our practices regarding the collection, use, storage, and disclosure of personal data, as well as the choices and rights available to you.

By using Gofile, you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any part of it, you should discontinue use of the Service.

Data Controller
---------------

The data controller responsible for the processing of personal data collected through the Gofile platform is:

Company: WOJTEK SAS

Address: 78, Avenue des Champs-Élysées, 75008 Paris, France

Registration: 889 963 708 R.C.S. Paris

Contact: [Contact Form](https://gofile.io/contact)

For subscription payments, the independent data controller for billing-related personal data is Number X Europe OÜ (reg. 16634149, Vesivärava tn 50-201, 10152 Tallinn, Estonia). Please refer to their privacy policy for information on how they process payment data.

Data We Collect
---------------

Gofile collects only the minimum data necessary to provide the Service. The information we collect depends on how you use the platform:

### Guest Access

When using Gofile as a guest without creating an account, we do not collect any personal data. A temporary session identifier is generated for technical purposes but is not linked to any identifiable individual.

### Free Account

When you create a free account, we collect and store your email address. This serves as your account identifier and is used exclusively to send you secure login links. No password is required or stored. We do not collect your name, phone number, physical address, or any other personal identifiers.

### Premium Account

When you upgrade to Premium, additional billing-related information is collected as necessary to process payments and generate invoices. This may include your name, billing address, and payment method details. For recurring subscriptions, this data is processed by our merchant of record, Number X Europe OÜ. For Pay-as-You-Go and one-shot yearly payments, this data is processed directly by WOJTEK SAS.

### Automatically Collected Data

Like most online services, our servers automatically log certain technical information when you access the platform, including your IP address, browser type, operating system, referring URLs, and timestamps of requests. These logs are retained for a limited period and are used exclusively for security, abuse prevention, rate limiting, and platform diagnostics. They are not used for profiling, tracking, or marketing purposes.

Purpose & Legal Basis for Processing
------------------------------------

We process personal data only for specified, explicit, and legitimate purposes, and we do not process data in a manner incompatible with those purposes. The legal basis for each processing activity is set out below:

| Purpose | Data Involved | Legal Basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Account creation & authentication | Email address | Performance of contract |
| Premium payment processing | Billing details, payment information | Performance of contract |
| Service communication (login links, payment confirmations, account notifications) | Email address | Performance of contract |
| Security, abuse prevention & rate limiting | IP address, server logs | Legitimate interest |
| Legal compliance (responding to lawful requests, maintaining records) | All collected data as necessary | Legal obligation |

Data Sharing & Third Parties
----------------------------

We do not sell, rent, or trade personal data to third parties. We do not share personal data with advertisers, data brokers, or analytics companies. Data is only shared in the following limited circumstances:

*   **Payment Processors:** For subscription payments, billing data is processed by our merchant of record, Number X Europe OÜ. For other payment methods, data may be shared with the payment provider strictly as necessary to complete the transaction.
*   **Infrastructure Providers:** Our servers and network infrastructure are operated by trusted hosting providers. These providers process data solely on our instructions and under contractual obligations that ensure equivalent data protection.
*   **Legal Compliance:** We may disclose data when required by law, such as in response to a valid court order, subpoena, or law enforcement request. We carefully review each request and only disclose the minimum data necessary to comply. Where permitted, we notify affected Users before disclosure.

Data Retention
--------------

Personal data is retained only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected, or as required by applicable law:

*   **Account Data:** Email addresses are retained for the duration of the account's existence. Upon account deletion, the email address is removed from our active systems.
*   **Billing Data:** Invoicing records are retained for the period required by applicable tax and accounting laws (typically 10 years under French law).
*   **Server Logs:** Technical logs containing IP addresses are retained for a short period (generally up to 30 days) and are then automatically purged, unless preservation is required for an ongoing security investigation or legal matter.
*   **User Content:** Files and folders uploaded by Users are retained according to the storage terms applicable to their account tier. Free accounts are subject to ephemeral storage; Premium accounts enjoy permanent storage. Deleted content is removed from our servers in a timely manner.

Data Security
-------------

We implement and maintain appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect personal data against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction:

### Encryption

All data transmitted to and from Gofile is encrypted in transit using TLS. Content stored on our servers is encrypted at rest. We strongly recommend Users encrypt sensitive files locally before uploading for an additional layer of protection.

### Access Control

Access to our servers and infrastructure is strictly limited to authorized personnel. Physical access to our datacenters is monitored, logged, and restricted through multiple layers of security.

### Authentication

Gofile uses a passwordless authentication system. Login links are sent exclusively to the User's registered email address and expire after use. This eliminates the risk of password-based attacks such as credential stuffing and brute force.

### Continuous Improvement

We regularly review and update our security practices to address evolving threats. Our infrastructure is designed with defense-in-depth principles, and we monitor for anomalies that may indicate unauthorized activity.

Cookies & Similar Technologies
------------------------------

Gofile uses only essential cookies and local storage that are strictly necessary for the operation of the platform. These include:

*   **Session & Authentication:** Technical tokens stored in your browser to maintain your login session and remember your preferences (such as selected upload proxy). These are essential for the Service to function.
*   **Guest Sessions:** A temporary identifier stored locally to associate your browser with a guest session for the duration of your visit.

We do not use tracking cookies, advertising cookies, analytics cookies, or any third-party cookies. We do not deploy fingerprinting scripts, beacons, or similar tracking technologies.

Your Rights
-----------

Under applicable data protection laws — including the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for Users in the European Economic Area — you have the following rights regarding your personal data:

### Right of Access

You may request confirmation of whether we process your personal data and obtain a copy of that data.

### Right of Rectification

You may request correction of inaccurate or incomplete personal data we hold about you.

### Right of Erasure

You may request deletion of your personal data, subject to legal retention obligations. You can delete your account and associated data at any time.

### Right to Restrict Processing

You may request that we limit how we process your data in certain circumstances defined by law.

### Right to Data Portability

You may request a copy of your data in a structured, machine-readable format for transfer to another service.

### Right to Object

You may object to processing based on legitimate interests. We will cease processing unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us through our [contact page](https://gofile.io/contact). We will respond to your request within the timeframe required by applicable law (generally within one month). We may need to verify your identity before processing your request. There is no fee for exercising these rights unless the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.

If you believe our processing of your personal data violates applicable law, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority — in France, the **Commission Nationale de l'Informatique et des Libertés (CNIL)** at [www.cnil.fr](https://www.cnil.fr/).

International Data Transfers
----------------------------

Gofile operates storage datacenters in Paris (France) and Phoenix (United States), with a global network of upload and download proxy servers. As a result, your Content may be stored and processed in jurisdictions outside your country of residence.

When we transfer personal data outside the European Economic Area, we ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place in accordance with applicable data protection laws. For transfers to the United States, we rely on standard contractual clauses or other legally recognized transfer mechanisms. Users concerned about data locality may select their preferred upload proxy region in their profile settings.

Changes to This Policy
----------------------

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our practices, technology, legal requirements, or the features of our Service. Material changes will be communicated to registered Users by email or through a notice on the platform. The latest version will always be available on this page. Continued use of the Service after changes take effect constitutes acceptance of the revised policy.

Contact & Questions
-------------------

For any questions about this Privacy Policy, to exercise your data protection rights, or to raise a concern about how we handle your personal data, please reach out through our [contact page](https://gofile.io/contact). We are committed to addressing all privacy-related inquiries promptly and transparently.
